A Finding Aid to the William Mills Ivins Papers, 1878-1964, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Publications, 1896-1958; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 13-14
  - "The Woodcuts to Vesalius," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXXI, no.7, 1936 July; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - "The Lovers by the Masters b x g. An Undescribed Early German Engraving," Metropolitan Museum Studies, vol. V pt. 2, 1936 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - "Goya's Giant," Metropolitan Museum Studies, vol. V, pt. 2, 1936 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - "Italian Renaissance Prints and Illustrated Books," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXXII, no. 12, 1937 December; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - "Italian Baroque Prints," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXXIII, no. 7, 1938 July; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - On the Rationalization of Sight: With an Examination of Three Renaissance Texts on Perspective. Metropolitan Museum of Art Papers, No. 8, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - "Address given at the Opening of the Exhibition of Metropolitan Museum Printing held in the Pierpont Morgan Library on 24, October 1938", 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - "The Ketham of 1490," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXXVI, no. 2, 1939 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - "The Artist and the Fifteenth-Century Printer", 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - "The Art of Rembrandt," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, no. 1, 1942 January; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - The Unseen Rembrandt by Ivins, reviewed by Jakob Rosenberg, College Art Journal, vol. I, no.4, 1942 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - "Rennaissance Books on Architecture," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1942 December; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - "Free Thought in the Country," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1943 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "A Breugel Exhibition in the Print Galleries," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1943 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Ignorance, the End," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1943 Summer; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "A Note on Girard Desargues," Scripta Mathematica, 1943 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - A Propos the Fabrica of Vesalius," Bulletin of the History of Medicine, 1943 December; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - How Prints Look, 1943; 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "The Herbal of 'Pseudo- Apuleius'," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, March 1944, 1944 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Early Florentine Illustrated Books," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Summer 1944, 1944 Summer; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "But It's Not a Cimabue!," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1944 December; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "French XVI Century Prints," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, June 1945, 1945 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "Goya," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1945 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "In the Beginning was the Word," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1945 Summer; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "The Art Museum Library," The Museum News, vol. 23, no. 8, 1954 October 15; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Preface to an American Philosophy of Art," by A. Phillip McMahon, reviewed by Ivins, Gazette des Beaux-Arts, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "Tiresome and Baroque," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1946 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "The Aix Lantern," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1946 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "The 'Field' of Prints, Objects vs. Meanings," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1946 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "The Dead Hand," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Buffalo Academy of Fine Arts Albright Gallery Notes, PSA [Photographic Society of America], 1947 January; 1946 June; 1947 November; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Address by William Ivins, Jr. in the Yale Art Gallery, Friday evening", 1946 October 18; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "The Dances of Death" Printed in Paris in 1490. A reproduction made from the copy in the Lessing J. Rosenwald Collection, Library of Congress, with an introduction by Ivins, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Art & Geometry: A Study in Space Intuition, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "A Few Fallacies About Art," Harper's, 1947 August; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - "More Fallacies About Art," Harper's, 1947 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - "A Note on Desargues' Theorum," Scripta Mathematica, 1947 September/ December; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - "Some Notes on Fakes," Magazine of Art, 1948 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - "A Note on Ipseity," The Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, 1948 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - " A Neglected Aspect of Early Print-Making," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1948 October; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - "Leonardo da Vinci: Paragone. A Comparison of the Arts," by Irma A. Richter, reviewed by Ivins, Times Literary Supplement, 1949 June 10; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - "Some Disconnected Notes About Drawings," Harper's, 1949 December; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Three Vesalian Essays to Accompany the Icones Anatomicae of 1934, with Samuel W. Lambert and Willy Wiegand, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - "'Symmetry' by Herman Weyl," Reviewed by Ivins, Magazine of Art, 1953 April; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - "Prints and Visual Communication", 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - "What Makes a Masterpiece?," 1953; Reprinted in Art Digest, 1954 March 15; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - "Prints: Technique and Expression", 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous, 1915, undated; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; (Box 15; 1 linear ft.)
  This series consists mainly of printed matter (neither by nor about William M. Ivins, Jr.). Most are presentation copies of articles, and other appear to have been saved by Ivins for research purposes. These cover a wide variety of topics, including: book arts, history of medicine, history of science and technology, calligraphy, history of printmaking, psychology of perception, physiology of vision, philosophy, and the U.S. legal and judicial systems.
  Additional miscellaneous materials include non-printed items relating to Ivins' personal life, such as banking records, receipts and invoices for personal purchases (excluding prints and books), drawings by Ivins, and notes and clippings regarding his legal career.
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-48)
  - Clippings, Advertising Circulars, etc., Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 49-50)
  - Receipts and Invoices, Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Banking Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Clippings and miscellaneous items regarding Ivins' legal career, including Barnes vs. Roosevelt, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 53-54)
- Ivins Family Papers, circa 1878-1964; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 16-20; 4.5 linear ft.)
  The Ivins Family Papers consist mainly of correspondence between relatives and friends of the Ivins, 1878-1964, and also include drawings, clippings, genealogies, and miscellaneous items.
  Correspondence between William M. Ivins, Jr., and his mother, Emma Yard Ivins, is extensive and wide-ranging. Included are letters from boarding school, c. 1890-1897, with childhood memorabilia such as grade reports, homework papers, a silhouette, and printed programs from school concerts and athletic events. His letters written while an undergraduate at Harvard, 1897-1901, and during his European trip of 1901-1902, reflect a growing interest in art. During some periods, mother and son corresponded almost daily. He frequently wrote in detail about progress with work, news of the museum, opinions about art, and activities of friends and colleagues, as well as commenting on daily life at home.
  Florence Wyman Ivins (Mrs. William M. Ivins) also wrote to her mother-in-law regularly, mainly family news which often included details of her husband's professional activities.
  The series is organized into eight subseries by individual:
  5.1: Genealogy, undated
  5.2: William M. Ivins, Jr., circa 1893-1964
  5.3: Barbara Ivins, circa 1923-1949
  5.4: Emma Yard Ivins, 1878-1940
  5.5: Florence Wyman Ivins, circa 1910-1948
  5.6: Katharine Ivins, 1890s-1962
  5.7: Margaret Ivins Holmes, 1890s-1954
  5.8: Sarah Mills Ivins, 1890s-1910
  5.9: William M. Ivins, Sr., 1885-1924
  Letters addressed to each particular person for whom a subseries exists are arranged alphabetically by sender and filed in chronological order within each name. Related clippings, estate papers, and miscellaneous items are filed with the papers of the person to whom they pertain. There are a few exceptions in this filing system: in cases where there is but one letter addressed to an individual, the item is filed with the papers of the sender, and the authorship clearly indicated in the description.
  - Genealogy, undated; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    Genealogy, notes on family history, and clippings about Ivins/Mills/Perrine families, and Ivins/Yard/Swift families.
    - Ivins/Yard/Swift Familes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ivins/Mills/Perrine Families, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - William M. Ivins, Jr., circa 1893-1964; 5.2; Archival Resource Key
    Letters from relatives include those from Barbara Ivins [daughter]; Emma Yard Ivins [mother]; Florence Wyman Ivins [wife]; James Sterling Yard Ivins [brother]; Katharine Ivins [sister]; Margaret Ivins Holmes [sister]; Sarah Ivins [neice or cousin]; William M. Ivins, Sr., [father]; William T. Mills [grandfather]; Annie Perrine [cousin]; Loraine Wyman Painter [sister-in-law]; Walter C. Wyman [father-in-law]; and Addie Yard [grandmother].
    Records concerning the estate of Ivins' estate include obituary, memorials and tributes; letters of condolence, A-Z (addressed to Barbara); and Ivins Collection of Prints and Illustrated Books, sales records and auction catalogs.
    - Letters from Barbara Ivins, 1922-1956; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Letters from Emma Y. Ivins, undated; circa 1893-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4-24)
    - Letters about Emma Y. Ivins Headstone, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Letters from Florence M. Ivins, undated; 1908-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26-37)
    - Letters from James S.Y. Ivins, undated; 1897-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Letters from Katharine Ivins, 1909-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 39-42)
    - Letters from Katharine Ivins, 1947-1961; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-15)
    - Letters from Margaret [Holmes] Ivins, 1890s-1954; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Letters from Sarah Ivins, 1947-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Sr., 1893-1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Letters from William T. Mills, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Letters from Annie Perrine, 1929-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Letters from Lorraine Wyman, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Letters from Walter C. Wyman, 1916-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Letters from Addie Yard, 1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Obituaries and Letters of Condolences, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Tributes, Memorials, and Related Materials, circa 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Material Concerning the Estate of William M. Ivins, Jr., 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 27-30)
  - Barbara Ivins, circa 1923-1949; 5.3; Archival Resource Key
    Barbara Ivins (1913-), daughter of William M. Ivins, Jr., and Florence Wyman Ivins, was the donor of the William M. Ivins, Jr. Papers. She is sometimes addressed as Barbi, Bubbles, Bubsey. Letters found here include those from Florence Wyman Ivins [mother]; Katharine Ivins [aunt], undated; and William M. Ivins, Jr., [father].
    - Letters from Florence Wyman, circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Katharine Ivins, circa 1923-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr., circa 1923-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Watercolors, Pencil Sketches, and Prints by Barbara Ivins, circa 1923-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Emma Yard Ivins, 1878-1940; 5.4; Archival Resource Key
    Emma Yard Ivins (1857-1940) was the mother of William M. Ivins, Jr. She was an amateur photographer whose work was exhibited at the turn of the century. She was active in the woman's suffrage movement from circa 1900 to 1915. She was sometimes addressed as Nem or Bammie.
    Material relating to the woman's suffrage movement includes letters from Susan B. Anthony, with a photographic portrait and a printed silhouette. Also included are letters from Ida Husted Harper and Anna H. Shaw. In addition, there is miscellaneous printed matter and undated impressions of the suffrage movement in England by an author unknown.
    Miscellaneous records include Christmas lists; constitution and by-laws of the Wednesday Afternoon Club, with lists of officers and programs since its establishment in 1888; a certificate from the Woodrow Wilson Foundation; and clippings about Emma Yard Ivins.
    Letters from relatives include those from James S. Y. Ivins [son]; Katharine Ivins [daughter]; Margaret Ivins Holmes and Jonathan Holmes [daughter and grandson]; Sarah Mills Ivins [mother-in-law]; William M. Ivins, Jr. [son]; and William M. Ivins, Jr., and Florence Wyman Ivins [son and daughter-in-law].
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1906-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
    - Re: Financial Matters, 1920-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Letters from Susan B. Anthony, 1900-1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Letters from Ida Harper, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Letters from Anna H. Shaw, 1906-1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material about Women's Suffrage Movement, circa 1900-1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Impressions of Suffrage Movement in England, circa 1900-1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Christmas Lists, 1900-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Wednesday Afternoon Club, 1917-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Certificate from Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1921; 1924; circa 1921-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Letters from James S.Y. Ivins, circa 1897-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Letters from Katharine Ivins, circa 1917-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Letters from Margaret [Ivins] Holmes and Jonathon Holmes, 1909-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Letters from Sarah M. Ivins (mother-in-law), circa 1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr., 1889; circa 1880-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr. from Boarding School (Stamford, Conn.), circa 1890-1893; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 22-26)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr. from Boarding School (Concord, N.H.), circa 1893-1897; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 27-32)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr. from St. Paul's School- Reports and Event Programs, 1893-1894; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr. from Harvard, circa 1897-1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 34-38)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr. from European trip, 1901-1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 39-40)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr., circa 1903-1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Letter from William and Florence W. Ivins, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr., 1911-1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 43-45)
    - Letters from William and Florence W. Ivins, circa 1914-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 46-59)
    - Letters from William and Florence W.Ivins, 1925-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1-17)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Sr., circa 1883-1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 18-20)
    - Letter from James S. Yard, 1878; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Florence Wyman Ivins, circa 1910-1948; 5.5; Archival Resource Key
    Florence Wyman Ivins was the wife of William M. Ivins, Jr., and an illustrator, primarily of children's books, and a painter of children's portraits. Many of her letters to family members are illustrated with pen and ink drawings or watercolors. She was addressed as Flossie of Flo.
    Letters from family and friends include those from Emma Yard Ivins [mother-in-law]; Katharine Ivins [sister-in-law]; Sarah Ivins; William M. Ivins, Jr. [husband]; Margaret Orr; Margaret Wind; Helen and Herbert Winlock; Wyman Family [letters from FWI to her father and sister].
    Artwork includes a sketchbook, Southold [L. I.], from the summer of 1922, containing watercolor and pencil sketches of local scenery, Barbara, WMI, Jr., Loraine Wyman, and Paderewski. Also found here are portraits of William M. Ivins, Jr, (2), Bruce Rogers, and Marion Stone; miscellaneous prints and drawings; Christmas and other greeting cards designed by FWI, circa 1910-1937, including a 1937 New Year's greeting, "A Parable of Artists and Art Critics" by Hans Christian Andersen, illustrated by FWI with calligraphy by WMI, Jr.
    Miscellaneous material includes notes about E.S. [Elizabeth Sears?]; a flyer advertising children's portraits by FWI, with snapshots of children [used for paintings?]; a marriage announcement and related clippings, 1910; and Wyman family obituaries, including FWI.
    Writings include childhood reminiscences and principles of art instruction at Brearly School.
    - Letter to Wyman Family, circa 1911- 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Letter from William M. Ivins, Jr., circa 1917- circa 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Letter to H.E. Winlock, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Letters from Family and Friends, 1940s; 1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Southold [L.I.] Sketchbook, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Portraits of William Ivins, Jr., Marion Stone, and Bruce Rogers, 1925; 1938; 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings and Prints, circa 1911-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Special Occasion Cards Designed by Florence Ivins, circa 1910-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 29-30)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1911-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Marriage Announcements and Clippings, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Clippings of Wyman Family Obituaries, circa 1911- circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Childhood Reminiscences, circa 1911-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Principles of Art Instruction at the Brearly School, circa 1911-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Katharine Ivins, 1890s-1962; 5.6; Archival Resource Key
    Katharine Ivins (circa 1888-) was the sister of William M.Ivins, Jr. A music teacher, she lived with mother in the Yard family home, in Freehold, N.J. She was addressed as Kate or Katti.
    Letters from relatives include those from Barbara Ivins [niece] Florence Wyman Ivins [sister-in-law]; Margaret Ivins Holmes [sister]; and William M. Ivins, Jr. [brother]. Writings include an essay [school homework], and a notebook, including childhood reminiscences with mention of mother's photography, schooling etc.
    - Letters from Barbara Ivins, 1926; 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Letters from Florence W. Ivins, 1918-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Letters from Margaret Ivins, circa 1890s-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr., circa 1890s-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 39-48)
    - Letters from Friends and Business Letters, circa 1890s-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous Writings by Katharine Ivins, circa 1890s-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Notebook, circa 1890s; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Margaret Ivins Holmes, 1890s-1954; 5.7; Archival Resource Key
    Margaret Ivins Holmes, (1882-1954), sister of William M. Ivins, Jr., lived in Freehold, N.J. and ran an antique store there with her husband, William Holmes. She was addressed as Margie or Peggy. Letters from relatives include those from Florence W. Ivins [sister-in-law]; William M. Ivins, Jr. [brother]; and William M. Ivins, Sr. [father].
    - Letters from Relatives, 1890s-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Sarah Mills Ivins, 1890s-1910; 5.8; Archival Resource Key
    - Letters from Emma Yard Ivins [daughter-in-law], and William M. Ivins, Jr. [grandson], 1890s-1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - William M. Ivins, Sr., 1885-1924; 5.9; Archival Resource Key
    William M. Ivins, Sr., (1851-1915), father of William M. Ivins, Jr., was a lawyer and politician and was addressed as Will. He spent a great deal of time in Europe and South America as a corporate lawyer. In 1905, he ran unsuccessfully for mayor of New York City. Business correspondence includes a letter from Mme. Blavatsky, with clippings and photographic portrait. Letters from relatives include those from Emma Yard Ivins [wife]; Katharine Ivins [daughter]; Margaret Ivins Holmes [daughter]; Sarah Mills Ivins [mother]; William M. Ivins, Jr. [son]; Annie Perrine [cousin]; James S. Yard [father-in-law]. Miscellaneous material includes biographical notes; clippings by and about WMI Sr., including an obituary; and miscellaneous notes copied from an unidentified publication.
    - Business- Copies of William M. Ivins, Sr. Letters, 1897-1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Blavotsky, circa 1891-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - Letters from Emma Ivins, circa 1891; 1924; 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Letter from Katharine Ivins, 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Letter from Margaret Ivins, 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Letters from William M. Ivins, Jr. from Boarding School, 1891-1897; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4)